In this section we're going to discuss the related areas of project management.
We know that projects are the only entity the only structure that can happen within the organization
and we're going to nail down those other areas that affect project management that you'll need to know
for your exam but also maybe in your organization.
So I want to have a really clear understanding here and look at these different terms.
And so if you know the terms that will help us pass the PMP by answering questions correctly.
So we're going to talk about the difference between project management program management and portfolio
management.
Those three things are related.
You might also be working in a project management office.
There's different types of project management offices.
Your organization might call it a PMO might call it a project office or a project headquarters.
So those all overlap for our sake we're just refer to it as a PMO a project management office.
We're going to really have a good distinction in the section about operations or projects we need to
be able to recognize is that a project or is it an operation or what's the difference or what are some
characteristics of both really important to be able to recognize is this that operational activity or
project activity.
So we're going to dive into that in the section you have an assignment where you'll test yourself on
projects or operations.
So that's really important and is a fun little exercise or fun may not be the right word but it's an
exercise or an assignment.
We're going to talk about OPM.
So a new term for you 0 p.m. So we'll look at OPM in business strategy.
How are those two things related.
Well what is OPM and business strategy something you look forward to in this section and then we'll
talk about understanding your project environment.
So we're going to discuss this and hopefully you'll be able to recognize the characteristics of different
environments and even the environment that you work in as a project manager.
So we have a lot of information to cover in this section.
So let's hop in and knock it out right now.
Keep moving forward.